After MIT Professor Joseph Weizenbaum created the chatbot Eliza, he became concerned that people who had used the programme started to act as if it was human.
麻省理工学院教授约瑟夫·魏岑鲍姆创建了聊天机器人伊莉莎之后，他担心使用过该程序的人开始表现得好像它是人类一样。
This might sound like a modern problem, but Eliza was created in 1966.
这听起来可能像是一个现代问题，但伊莉莎是1966年被制造出来的。
If a programme from the 1960s was capable of tricking people into thinking it was human, what effect could the large-language-model-based chatbots of the 2020s have?
如果一个来自20世纪60年代的程序能够欺骗人们以为它是人类，那么21世纪20年代基于大语言模型的聊天机器人会产生什么影响呢？
Modern philosophers and technology experts have discussed whether AI could develop consciousness.
现代哲学家和技术专家们讨论了人工智能是否可能发展出意识。
Sentience is difficult to define, but the fact that large language models respond by mathematically calculating the probability of certain patterns appearing suggests that it would be hard to consider them to be alive.
感知力很难定义，但大语言模型通过数学计算特定模式出现的概率来做出回应，这一事实表明很难将它们视为有生命的。
However, in terms of our responses to them, what matters is not whether they are sentient, but whether they appear to be so.
然而，就我们对它们的反应而言，重要的不是它们是否有感知力，而是它们是否看起来有感知力。
Large language models are made up of genuine human interactions.
大语言模型是由真实的人类互动构成的。
While their tendency to hallucinate means that chatbots are not able to provide reliable factual information, they are able to effectively replicate the language used in human communication.
虽然它们有时会出现幻觉，意味着聊天机器人无法提供可靠的事实信息，但它们能够有效地复制人类交流中使用的语言。
Psychologists report that people tend to have a cognitive bias towards forming attachment and trust.
心理学家报告说，人们往往有一种认知偏差，倾向于形成依恋和信任。
Even sceptical technology writers report feeling some emotion towards AI chatbots.
即使是持怀疑态度的科技作家也表示对人工智能聊天机器人产生了一些情感。
Some users have even reported grief when one model has been replaced by a newer one.
一些用户甚至报告说，当一个模型被更新的模型取代时，他们感到悲伤。
This combination of believable human language together with the inability to reliably assess facts can be dangerous.
这种真实可信的人类语言与无法可靠地评估事实的结合可能是危险的。
Cases have been reported where people have been encouraged by chatbots to do dangerous or illegal things.
已有报道称，聊天机器人鼓励人们做危险或非法的事情。
The chatbots were able to use language to encourage and persuade, but not identify or evaluate risks.
聊天机器人能够使用语言来鼓励和说服，但无法识别或评估风险。
Trust becomes dangerous when it is not accompanied by reason.
当信任没有理性相伴时，它就变得危险。
Also, if people form relationships with AI, then they may spend less time and effort trying to cultivate genuine human relationships.
此外，如果人们与人工智能建立关系，那么他们可能会花更少的时间和精力去培养真正的人际关系。
Could the chatbot revolution lead to a world where we struggle to relate to each other?
聊天机器人的变革会导致一个我们人类之间难以相互联系的世界吗？